
export const quiz = {
    totalQuestions: 30,
    questions: [
      {
        id: 1,
        question: "What is the maximum number of moves that can be played in a chess game?",
        answers: ["476", "5949", "10000", "832"],
        correctAnswer: "5949"
      },
      {
        id: 2,
        question: "Which piece can move diagonally any number of squares?",
        answers: ["King", "Bishop", "Queen", "Knight"],
        correctAnswer: "Bishop"
      },
      {
        id: 3,
        question: "Can a pawn move backward?",
        answers: ["Yes", "No", "Only if promoted", "Varies"],
        correctAnswer: "No"
      },
      {
        id: 4,
        question: "What is the only piece in chess that can never move to the opposite color squares on the board?",
        answers: ["King", "Queen", "Rook", "Bishop"],
        correctAnswer: "Bishop"
      },
      {
        id: 5,
        question: "What is a stalemate in chess?",
        answers: ["Checkmate", "Draw", "Resign", "Stale"],
        correctAnswer: "Draw"
      },
      {
        id: 6,
        question: "How many pawns does each player start with?",
        answers: ["4", "6", "8", "10"],
        correctAnswer: "8"
      },
      {
        id: 7,
        question: "Which piece can move only one square in any direction?",
        answers: ["Bishop", "Rook", "Knight", "King"],
        correctAnswer: "King"
      },
      {
        id: 8,
        question: "What is the value of a pawn in chess?",
        answers: ["1", "2", "3", "4"],
        correctAnswer: "1"
      },
      {
        id: 9,
        question: "What is the name of the move where a pawn captures an opponent's pawn by moving diagonally?",
        answers: ["Check", "Mate", "Castle", "En passant"],
        correctAnswer: "En passant"
      },
      {
        id: 10,
        question: "What is the name of the move in chess where a pawn moves two squares forward from its starting position?",
        answers: ["Promotion", "Checkmate", "Castling", "Advance"],
        correctAnswer: "Advance"
      },
      {
        id: 11,
        question: "Which piece is often considered the most powerful in the opening stage of the game?",
        answers: ["Rook", "Queen", "Knight", "Bishop"],
        correctAnswer: "Queen"
      },
      {
        id: 12,
        question: "In chess notation, what does 'O-O' signify?",
        answers: ["Mate", "En passant", "Kingside castling", "Check"],
        correctAnswer: "Kingside castling"
      },
      {
        id: 13,
        question: "What is the purpose of castling in chess?",
        answers: ["Attack", "Defense", "Draw", "Sacrifice"],
        correctAnswer: "Defense"
      },
      {
        id: 14,
        question: "What is the only piece that can move to any square on the board in a single move?",
        answers: ["Queen", "Bishop", "Knight", "King"],
        correctAnswer: "Knight"
      },
      {
        id: 15,
        question: "How many squares can a knight move in a single turn?",
        answers: ["4", "6", "8", "10"],
        correctAnswer: "8"
      },
      {
        id: 16,
        question: "What is the starting position of the queen on the chessboard?",
        answers: ["Center", "Corner", "Adjacent", "In front"],
        correctAnswer: "Adjacent"
      },
      {
        id: 17,
        question: "What is the only piece that cannot be captured by moving onto its square?",
        answers: ["Queen", "Rook", "Bishop", "Knight"],
        correctAnswer: "Knight"
      },
      {
        id: 18,
        question: "What is the term for a situation in which neither player can deliver checkmate?",
        answers: ["Checkmate", "Stalemate", "Draw", "Resign"],
        correctAnswer: "Stalemate"
      },
      {
        id: 19,
        question: "What is the smallest number of moves required for a pawn to reach the opposite side of the board and be promoted?",
        answers: ["1", "2", "3", "4"],
        correctAnswer: "4"
      },
      {
        id: 20,
        question: "What does the term 'en passant' mean in chess?",
        answers: ["Capture", "Promotion", "Exchange", "Special pawn capture"],
        correctAnswer: "Special pawn capture"
      },
      {
        id: 21,
        question: "Which piece is typically developed first in the opening phase of a chess game?",
        answers: ["Rook", "Bishop", "Knight", "Queen"],
        correctAnswer: "Knight"
      },
      {
        id: 22,
        question: "In chess notation, what does the symbol '+' represent?",
        answers: ["Stalemate", "Checkmate", "Check", "Draw"],
        correctAnswer: "Check"
      },
      {
        id: 23,
        question: "What is the maximum number of queens a player can have on the board at once?",
        answers: ["1", "2", "8", "9"],
        correctAnswer: "9"
      },
      {
        id: 24,
        question: "What is the name of the move where the king and rook move past each other?",
        answers: ["Check", "En passant", "Castling", "Promotion"],
        correctAnswer: "Castling"
      },
      {
        id: 25,
        question: "What is the primary objective of chess?",
        answers: ["Promotion", "Draw", "Checkmate", "Sacrifice"],
        correctAnswer: "Checkmate"
      },
      {
        id: 26,
        question: "How many squares does a bishop control if it's placed in the center of the board?",
        answers: ["7", "11", "13", "15"],
        correctAnswer: "13"
      },
      {
        id: 27,
        question: "What is the value of a bishop in chess?",
        answers: ["1", "2", "3", "4"],
        correctAnswer: "3"
      },
      {
        id: 28,
        question: "Which piece is commonly referred to as the \"little brother\"?",
        answers: ["Queen", "Rook", "Bishop", "Knight"],
        correctAnswer: "Knight"
      },
      {
        id: 29,
        question: "What is the term for a move that threatens the opponent's king?",
        answers: ["Promotion", "En passant", "Check", "Mate"],
        correctAnswer: "Check"
      },
      {
        id: 30,
        question: "What is the term for a player who has no legal moves and whose king is not in check?",
        answers: ["Stalemate", "Win", "Lose", "Castling"],
        correctAnswer: "Stalemate"
      }
    ]
  };
  